<rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
     xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>RT World News</title>
        <link>https://www.rt.com/news/</link>
        <description>RT World News</description>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 20:59:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <copyright>RT</copyright>
        <atom:link href="https://www.rt.com/rss/news" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <image>
            <url>https://www.rt.com/static/img/logo-rss.png</url>
            <title>RT World News</title>
            <link>https://www.rt.com</link>
            <width>125</width>
            <height>40</height>
        </image>
        <item>
            <title>World Bank suspends payments to Mali in bid to put pressure on military junta after latest coup
            </title>
            <link>
                <![CDATA[ https://www.rt.com/news/525721-world-bank-suspends-mali-payments-coup/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=RSS ]]>
            </link>
            <guid>https://www.rt.com/news/525721-world-bank-suspends-mali-payments-coup/</guid>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[ <img alt="Preview" align="left" style="margin-right: 10px;" src="https://cdni.rt.com/files/2021.06/thumbnail/60ba852020302749d200c44b.JPG" /> The World Bank has announced it is temporarily cutting its payments to Mali after the Sahel nation’s government was ousted by the military last week in the country’s second coup in nine months. <br/><a href="https://www.rt.com/news/525721-world-bank-suspends-mali-payments-coup/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=RSS">Read Full Article at RT.com</a> ]]>
            </description>
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[ <p><strong>The World Bank has announced it is temporarily cutting its payments to Mali after the Sahel nation’s government was ousted by the military last week in the country’s second coup in nine months.</strong></p> <p>Mali&rsquo;s interim president Bah Ndaw and other leading officials were rounded up and arrested by soldiers last Monday for allegedly failing in their efforts to lead the country&rsquo;s democratic transition after a military coup in August.</p> <p>The World Bank, which is currently funding $1.5 billion worth of projects in Mali, informed news agency Reuters of the suspension.</p> <p><em>&ldquo;In accordance with the World Bank policy applicable to similar situations, it has temporarily paused disbursements on its operations in Mali, as it closely monitors and assesses the situation,&rdquo;</em> the bank said in a statement.</p> ]]>
                <![CDATA[ <blockquote> <span><strong>Also on rt.com</strong></span> <figure> <img src="https://cdni.rt.com/files/2021.06/thumbnail/60b93e8285f54075922dd3bd.jpg" alt="FILE PHOTO: French soldiers keep watch during a military convoy&#039;s trip between Gossi and Hombori in Mali, March 26, 2019 © AFP / Daphne Benoit" /> <figcaption><a href="/news/525608-france-stops-joint-operations-mali/">France suspends joint military operations with Mali in bid to force ruling junta to transfer power back to civilian leaders</a></figcaption> </figure> </blockquote> ]]>
                <![CDATA[ <p>Colonel Assimi Goita, who led the two coups, was declared president late last week after having previously served as vice president under Ndaw.</p> <p>According to local reports, Goita will name the leader of opposition coalition M5-RFP, Choguel Maiga, as prime minister.</p> <p>He has also pledged to continue with Mali&rsquo;s scheduled elections, which are planned for 2022.</p> <p>Mali&rsquo;s military has faced growing regional and international pressure over the coup, with France announcing the suspension of all of its joint operations with the country on Thursday.</p> ]]>
                <![CDATA[ <blockquote> <span><strong>Also on rt.com</strong></span> <figure> <img src="https://cdni.rt.com/files/2021.05/thumbnail/60acc0be2030274855427ea7.JPG" alt="FILE PHOTO. The interim president of Mali Bah Ndaw." /> <figcaption><a href="/news/524734-un-africa-mali-coup/">UN, African Union call for ‘immediate & unconditional’ release of Mali’s president and key officials detained by military</a></figcaption> </figure> </blockquote> ]]>
                <![CDATA[ <p>The French Defense Ministry said its suspension is a <em>&ldquo;conservative and temporary measure&rdquo;</em> pending guarantees from Mali&rsquo;s interim military leader that the elections in February of next year will take place.</p> <p>Mali&rsquo;s military has also received backlash from within the continent, with both the African Union (AU) and the Economic Community of West African States (ECOWAS) announcing the country&rsquo;s expulsion from the groups this week.</p> <p>Unlike ECOWAS, which did not take further measures against Mali, the AU threatened the country with sanctions.</p> <p>On Friday, at a rally in the Malian capital Bamako, Maiga told the crowds that <em>&ldquo;sanctions and threats will only complicate the situation.&rdquo;</em></p> <p><strong><em>Like this story? Share it with a friend!</em></strong></p> ]]>
            </content:encoded>
            <enclosure url="https://cdni.rt.com/files/2021.06/thumbnail/60ba852020302749d200c44b.JPG" type="image/jpeg"
                       length="123"/>
            <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 19:55:39 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>RT</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>SHOCKING VIDEO shows mob beating Indian doctor after death of Covid patient</title>
            <link>
                <![CDATA[ https://www.rt.com/news/525715-india-mob-beating-doctor/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=RSS ]]>
            </link>
            <guid>https://www.rt.com/news/525715-india-mob-beating-doctor/</guid>
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[ <p><strong>Police in Assam, India, have arrested 24 people after a mob brutally beat a doctor following the death of a coronavirus patient. Video footage of the shocking beatdown went viral.</strong></p> <p>Dr Seuj Kumar Senapati was beaten with brooms, whips and even bedpans at a rural clinic in Assam earlier this week, the <a href="https://indianexpress.com/article/north-east-india/assam/assam-doctor-assaulted-after-covid-19-patient-dies-arrested-ima-7340636/">Indian Express</a> reported on Thursday. Senapati, the Express reported, had been assigned to work in the clinic to treat coronavirus patients, one of whom died on Tuesday.</p> <p>The mob which attacked Senapati was reportedly made up of family members and friends of the deceased patient.</p> <p>Video footage shared on social media purportedly shows Senapati cowering on the ground as the enraged mob rains down blows on him. The person filming the shocking incident appears to be repeatedly telling the attackers to stop, to no avail.</p> <blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">HCM <a href="https://twitter.com/himantabiswa?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@himantabiswa</a> sir.<br>Look for youself !!<br>This is the condition of our FRONTLINE WARRIORS DOCTORS in ASSAM.<br>We are bearing the burden of incompetency.<a href="https://twitter.com/DGPAssamPolice?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@DGPAssamPolice</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/gpsinghassam?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@gpsinghassam</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/PMOIndia?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@PMOIndia</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/assampolice?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@assampolice</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/nhm_assam?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@nhm_assam</a> <a href="https://t.co/V3mVK8QNxN">pic.twitter.com/V3mVK8QNxN</a></p>&mdash; Dr. Kamal debnath (@debnath_aryan) <a href="https://twitter.com/debnath_aryan/status/1399731481316974592?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 1, 2021</a></blockquote> <script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script> <p>The doctor is then led outside, where the attack continues.</p> <blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">I dare you can&#39;t see whole vedio ..<br>How can anyone be like this👇 😨 <a href="https://t.co/rOHEvbTfh9">pic.twitter.com/rOHEvbTfh9</a></p>&mdash; Indian doctor (@Indian__doctor) <a href="https://twitter.com/Indian__doctor/status/1399759994988339200?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 1, 2021</a></blockquote> <script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script> <p>Still images posted afterwards apparently show Senapati covered in bruises and lacerations.</p> <blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Condition of INDIAN DOCTORS👇The pictures tells the story 😓<br><br>Dr. Seuj kumar Senapati , Medical officer, Posted in Udali Model Hospital, Hojai ( Passed out Student from Tezpur Medical college and hospital) he joined the duty as a MO under NRHM just few days ago. <a href="https://t.co/hzsjwoCXdh">pic.twitter.com/hzsjwoCXdh</a></p>&mdash; Indian doctor (@Indian__doctor) <a href="https://twitter.com/Indian__doctor/status/1399725977803034633?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 1, 2021</a></blockquote> <script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script> <p>As the videos went viral, Assam&rsquo;s Chief Minister, Himanta Biswa Sarma, <a href="https://twitter.com/himantabiswa/status/1399923786598678528">announced</a> on Wednesday that <em>&ldquo;24 culprits involved in this barbaric attack have been arrested and the chargesheet will be filed at the earliest.&rdquo;</em> Sarma added that he is <em>&ldquo;personally monitoring this investigation&rdquo; and promised that &ldquo;justice will be served.&rdquo;</em></p> <p>Assam is one of India&rsquo;s less densely populated states, but has still been hit hard by Covid-19. More than 4,500 new cases of the disease were reported there on Friday, along with 54 deaths. Altogether, India has seen the world&rsquo;s second-highest number of cases, at 28.6 million, and third-highest number of deaths, at more than 342,000.</p> ]]>
                <![CDATA[ <blockquote> <span><strong>Also on rt.com</strong></span> <figure> <img src="https://cdni.rt.com/files/2021.06/thumbnail/60b8f5622030270dfe72af6d.JPG" alt="Indian doctors performs endoscopic sinus surgery on a ‘black fungus’ patient. © Reuters / Adnan Abidi" /> <figcaption><a href="/news/525586-delhi-india-black-fungus/">Delhi reports more than 1,000 cases of ‘black fungus’ amid shortage of drugs to treat deadly Covid-linked disease</a></figcaption> </figure> </blockquote> ]]>
                <![CDATA[ <p><strong><em>Think your friends would be interested? Share this story!</em></strong></p> ]]>
            </content:encoded>
            <enclosure url="https://cdni.rt.com/files/2021.06/thumbnail/60ba643f20302749ca5b206d.png" type="image/jpeg"
                       length="123"/>
            <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 18:26:16 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>RT</dc:creator>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Nigeria suspends Twitter’s operations ‘indefinitely’ after president’s tweet removed from platform
            </title>
            <link>
                <![CDATA[ https://www.rt.com/news/525716-nigeria-suspends-twitter-operations/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=RSS ]]>
            </link>
            <guid>https://www.rt.com/news/525716-nigeria-suspends-twitter-operations/</guid>
            <description>
                <![CDATA[ <img alt="Preview" align="left" style="margin-right: 10px;" src="https://cdni.rt.com/files/2021.06/thumbnail/60ba660a20302753c61eb0b3.png" /> The Nigerian government has temporarily banned Twitter’s operations in the country after a tweet from President Muhammadu Buhari was removed by the social media platform for violating its “abusive behavior” policy. <br/><a href="https://www.rt.com/news/525716-nigeria-suspends-twitter-operations/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=RSS">Read Full Article at RT.com</a> ]]>
            </description>
            <content:encoded>
                <![CDATA[ <p><strong>The Nigerian government has temporarily banned Twitter’s operations in the country after a tweet from President Muhammadu Buhari was removed by the social media platform for violating its “abusive behavior” policy.</strong></p> <p>Buhari&rsquo;s account was also slapped with a 12-hour ban over Tuesday&rsquo;s offending post, which referenced the bloody 1967-70 Nigerian Civil War, during which more than one million people died.</p> <p>Nigeria&rsquo;s Minister of Information and Culture, Alhaji Lai Mohammed, announced the action against Twitter on Friday, saying the US-based firm&rsquo;s Nigerian operations would be<em> &ldquo;suspended indefinitely.&rdquo;</em></p> <p>He also cited Twitter&rsquo;s <em>&ldquo;persistent use of the platform for activities that are capable of undermining Nigeria&rsquo;s corporate existence.&rdquo;</em></p> <p>A ministry spokesperson said the government has asked Nigeria&rsquo;s TV regulator, the National Broadcasting Commission, to <em>&ldquo;immediately commence&rdquo;</em> the process for all social media companies and digital broadcasters to be licensed.</p> ]]>
                <![CDATA[ <blockquote> <span><strong>Also on rt.com</strong></span> <figure> <img src="https://cdni.rt.com/files/2021.06/thumbnail/60b8296f20302731b846dd67.jpg" alt="FILE PHOTOS." /> <figcaption><a href="/news/525522-nigerian-president-tweet-deleted/">Twitter scrubs Nigerian president’s post & suspends account for ‘abusive behavior’ after tweeting warning to rebels</a></figcaption> </figure> </blockquote> ]]>
                <![CDATA[ <p>In a statement Twitter said it is investigating Nigeria&rsquo;s <em>&ldquo;deeply concerning&rdquo;</em> suspension of its operations, saying it will <em>&ldquo;provide updates when we know more.&rdquo;</em></p> <p>A spokesperson for the platform issued a short statement after Buhari&rsquo;s tweet on Tuesday, saying it <em>&ldquo;was in violation of the Twitter Rules.&rdquo;</em></p> <p><em>&ldquo;The account owner will be required to delete the violative Tweet and spend 12 hours with their account in read-only mode,&rdquo;</em> it added.</p> <p>The president&rsquo;s now-deleted post had read: <em>&ldquo;Many of those misbehaving today are too young to be aware of the destruction and loss of lives that occurred during the Nigerian Civil War.&nbsp;</em><em>Those of us in the fields for 30 months, who went through the war, will treat them in the language they understand.&rdquo;</em></p> ]]>
                <![CDATA[ <blockquote> <span><strong>Also on rt.com</strong></span> <figure> <img src="https://cdni.rt.com/files/2021.05/thumbnail/60abd50585f54041b61296f1.jpg" alt="Residents of Gauraka community in Tafa Local Government Area of Niger State set bonfire on the Kaduna-Abuja highway in Gauruka, near Abuja, Nigeria, on May 24, 2021 during a protest against incessant kidnapping and killing after gunmen kidnapped 16 residents and killed three others in Niger State." /> <figcaption><a href="/news/524685-protests-blockade-nigerian-highway-kidnappings/">Protesters blockade Nigerian highway with burning tires over demand for greater security after kidnappers terrorize region</a></figcaption> </figure> </blockquote> ]]>
                <![CDATA[ <p>The Nigerian Civil War erupted in 1967 after the government&rsquo;s armed forces surrounded the independent state of Biafra in the south of the country, with many civilians dying, mostly from starvation. The territory&rsquo;s independence push has been sustained by separatist groups, such as the Indigenous Peoples of Biafra (IPOB) movement, which the government has designated a terrorist organization.</p> <p>Buhari did not refer to a specific organization or people in his tweet, although his administration has accused IPOB of carrying out several attacks, including on police stations and election offices.</p> <p>The president has come under fire in Nigeria for appearing to use stronger language in his tweet than he has done to condemn attacks by Boko Haram militants and other groups in the north of the country.</p> <p><strong><em>Think your friends would be interested? Share this story!</em></strong></p> ]]>
            </content:encoded>
            <enclosure url="https://cdni.rt.com/files/2021.06/thumbnail/60ba660a20302753c61eb0b3.png" type="image/jpeg"
                       length="123"/>
            <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 17:56:17 +0000</pubDate>
            <dc:creator>RT</dc:creator>
        </item>


    </channel>
</rss>